A Guide to the Records of the Virginia Liaison Office, 2003-2010 (bulk 2006-2009).
Library of Virginia
- Director's correspondence and subject files, 2003-2010., Extent: 3.85 cubic feet (11 boxes)
  - Director Jan Faircloth, 2002-2005
    - Justice Assistance Grant Programs (JAG), 2005. (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Maritime Security, 2005. (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - NASA - New Spaceship, 2005. (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - National Aboretum, 2005. (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - National Center for Integrated Systems Technology, undated. (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - National Governor's Association Conference, 2004 Feb. (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - National Governor's Association Conference, 2004 July. (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - National Governor's Association Conference, 2005 Feb. (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Natural Resources - State Wildlife Grants, 2005. (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Nature Conservancy requests, 2004. (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Non-Native Oysters, 2003. (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Prepositioned Equipment Program, 2004. (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - REAL ID, 2005. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Southern Governors' Association - Conference, 2004 Sept. (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Unfunded Mandate Reform Act, 2003. (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - U.S. Airways, 2002. (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Virginia Employment Commission - Unemployment Compensation, 2005. (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Visa H-2B, 2005. (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Policy Analyst files, 2005-2010., Extent: 4.55 cubic feet (13 boxes)
  This series includes the reference and research files of multiple federal policy analysts in the Virginia Liaison Office. These files are arranged alphabetically by topic and include briefing materials, correspondence, fact sheets, federal appropriation requests, legislation, presentations, promotional/informational materials, notes, publications, reports, and testimony before Congress. Policy Analysts included Aaron Ver (2005 Dec-2007), Dominic Gabello (2007 Jan-2008 Feb), Shaylah Nunn (2007-2009), Melinda Glazer (2008 Feb-2009 June), Aaron Turner (2009 May-Nov), and Kwame Boadi (2009 Oct-2010 Jan).
  - Air quality, 2006. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Air quality - Particle Pollution briefing, 2006. (Box 12)
  - American Association of Port Authorities, undated. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - American Youth Policy Forum / Youth Development Institute, 2008. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Attorney General, U.S., 2008. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Benton Foundation - National Broadband Strategy, 2007-2008. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Boeing, 2009. (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Base Realignment and Closure (BRAC), 2008-2009. (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Business Activity Tax Simplification Act (HR 5267), 2008. (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Byrne / Justice Assistance Grant (JAG) Program, 2008. (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Campus Security, 2007. (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Capital Beltway Proposal, 2007. (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Center for American Progress, 2008. (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Chesapeake Bay, 2007-2009. (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Chesapeake, Virginia - Transportation and Public Safety, 2008. (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Chesapeake's Healthy and Environmentally Sound Stewardship of Energy and Agriculture Act (CHESSEA), 2007. (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Clean Watershed Act, 2006. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Climate Change, 2007-2008. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Climate Change, 2007-2008. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Congressional Black Caucus - Annual Legislative Conference, 2008. (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Congressional Research Service Reports (Environmental), 2006. (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Constituent Correspondence - IQ Mail, 2008. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Constituent Correspondence - IQ Mail instructions, undated. (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Criminal Justice Services, Dept. of, 2008. (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Defense - U.S. Fleet, 2009. (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Defense Appropriations FY2010, 2009. (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs hearing (House Committee on Veterans' Affairs), 2008. (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - District of Columbia, 2007-2009. (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Economic Recovery, 2009. (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Education, 2006-2008. (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Education, 2008. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Education - American Youth Policy Forum, 2009. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Education - Child and School Nutrition, 2008-2009. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Education - Child Nutrition Act of 1966, 2008. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Education - Green School Construction (HR 3021), 2008. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Education - High School Graduation Outcomes bill (Rahm), 2008. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Education - P16 Council, 2008. (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Education - Rural Schools (HR3058), 2008. (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Education - Student Loan Market Crisis, 2008. (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Education - Student Loans (FFELP and Sallie Mae), 2009. (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Education - Student Loans and FERPA, 2008. (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Education Funding - American Recovery and Reinvestment Act, 2009. (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Election Working Group, 2008. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Election Working Group, 2008. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Energy Efficiency - Sustainable and Renewable Energy (HR 6049), 2008. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Energy Efficiency and Conservation, 2006. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - eStem bill, 2008. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Farm Bill, 2007. (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Federal Unemployment Tax Act (FUTA) / Virginia Employment Commission (VEC), 2007. (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Federal Workers Compensation, 2008. (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Federally Chartered Banks, 2008. (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - FEMA - Appropriation, 2009. (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - FEMA / Homeland Security, 2009. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Financial Services Regulatory Reform, 2009. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Foreclosure Prevention, undated. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Foster Care, 2008. (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Future Combat Systems, 2009. (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Government Finance Officers Association, 2008. (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Governor Kaine's Proposed Budget FY2008-2010 - Briefing, 2007 Dec 17. (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Grant Award Notices - Dept. of Justice, 2009. (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - H1N1 Flu, 2009. (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Health Insurance Reform, 2007-2008. (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Health Insurance Reform, 2009. (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Health Insurance Reform - Generic drugs, 2008. (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Higher Education, 2007. (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Highlands Action Program, undated. (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Homeland Security, 2007. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - HOT Lanes, 2008. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Housing Finance Agencies (HFA), 2009. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Immigration, 2007. (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Immigration - Visas, 2008. (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Immigration - Visas, 2009. (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Inauguration, 2009. (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Inmate request, 2008. (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - International Benchmarking, 2008-2009. (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Justice Center - Reentry Programs and Second Chance Act, 2007. (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Justice for All Act, 2008. (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Lewiston Interchange (Hanover County), 2007. (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Mad Cow Disease / Creutzfeldt-Jakob Disease, 2008. (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Metropolitan Washington Airports Authority / Dulles, 2008. (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Military Mission Growth, 2008. (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous, 2007-2009. (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous - Notes (Aaron), undated. (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - National Aeronautics and Space Adminsitration - Ares I-X Flight Test, 2009. (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - National Aeronautics and Space Administration - FAA - Commercial Space Flight, 2008. (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - National Aeronautics and Space Administration - Langley Research Center, 2008-2009. (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - National Aeronautics and Space Administration - Mid-Atlantic Regional Spaceport (MARS), 2008-2009. (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - National Aeronautics and Space Administration - Miscellaneous, 2008-2009. (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - National Governors Association, 2007-2009. (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - National Governors Association - Awards, 2007. (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - National Governors Association - Education, Early Childhood and Workforce Committee, 2008-2009. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - National Governors Association - Federal-State Partnership, 2008. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - National Governors Association - Forum on College and Career Readiness, 2008. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - National Governors Association - Innovation America, 2006. (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - National Governors Association - Public Safety, 2008-2009. (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - National Governors Association - National Guard, 2009. (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - National Governors Association - State Summit on Innovative Transportation Funding and Financing, 2008. (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - National Governors Association - Transportation, 2008. (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - National Guard, 2007. (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - National Guard, 2008-2009. (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Natural Gas Decoupling, 2006. (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Newport News Wastewater, 2007. (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - No Child Left Behind, 2008. (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - No Child Left Behind - Final Regulations Briefing, 2008. (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Offshore Drilling, 2006-2009. (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD), 2007. (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Outlying Landing Field (OLF), 2007. (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Pre-K Act (HR 3289), 2008. (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - President's Budget FY2008, 2007. (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Privacy, undated. (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Public Safety (miscellaneous), 2009. (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Radden - 80th Birthday Request, 2008. (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Radford Army Ammunition Plant, 2008. (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - REAL ID, 2005-2008. (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - REAL ID, 2006. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - REAL ID, 2007. (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - REAL ID / PASS ID, 2000. (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - REAL ID - Regulations, 2007. (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Renewable Energy, 2006. (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Rolls Royce - Joint Strike Fighter Engine, undated. (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Safe Prisons Communications Act, 2009. (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Soldier Casualties, 2006. (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Southern Governors' Association, 2007-2009. (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Statewide Agencies Radio System (STARS), 2007. (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Teach for America, 2008. (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Tobacco Control Act (HR 1108), 2008. (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Trade, 2006-2007. (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Transportation briefing, 2007. (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Transportation - American Recovery and Reinvestment Act (ARRA), 2009. (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Transportation - Amtrak / Rail transportation, 2008-2009. (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Transportation - Appalachian Development Highway System, 2009. (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Transportation - Federal Aviation Authority (FAA) Act, 2009. (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Transportation - High Speed Rail, 2007-2009. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Transportation - HOT Lanes, 2008-2009. (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Transportation - Jackson Gateway Interchange (Spotsylvania County), 2008. (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Transportation - Kerley testimony to House Transportation and Infrastructure Committee (bridges), 2007. (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Transportation - Lewiston Road Interchange (Hanover County), 2007. (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Transportation - Miscellaneous, 2009. (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Transportation - National Infrastructure Development Bank, 2009. (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Transportation - PrePass, 2009. (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Transportation - REAL ID, 2006-2007. (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Transportation - Reports and presentations, 2008-2009. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Transportation - Research and Development (HR 2569), 2009. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Transportation Reauthorization and Donor Equity, 2007-2009. (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Transportation Security Administration (TSA) authorization, 2009. (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Trends in International Mathematics and Science Study, 2007-2008. (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Trust for Public Land (Jamestown), 2006. (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Veterans Center (VCU), 2007. (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Virginia Center for Policing Innovation, undated. (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Virginia National Guard, 2008-2009. (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Virginia Tourism Corp., 2007-2008. (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Virginia Sesquicentennial of the American Civil War Commission, 2007. (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Water Protection and Reinvestment Act (WPRA) (HR 3202), 2009. (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Watergate Condominiums, 2009. (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - White House Clean Energy Economy Forum, 2009. (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Women in Government Relations, 2008. (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Workforce Development, 2007. (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Workforce Investment Act, 2006-2007. (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Youth Build USA, 2008. (Box 24, Folder 7)
- Congressional Delegation Briefings, 2006-2009., Extent: 1.05 cubic feet (3 boxes)
  This series includes Congressional Delegation Briefing binders and Federal Priority binders. The Virginia Liaison Office (VLO) assists in influencing the development of federal legislation by keeping the the Virginia State Congressional Delegation informed about the Governor's policy and budget concerns. The Governor and his Cabinet meet annually with the Virginia Congressional Delegation to discuss these major legislative and regulatory priorities. The Congressional Delegation Briefing binders and Federal Priority binders are developed by the VLO in conjunction with the Governor and his Cabinet, and are distributed to meeting participants. The binders are organized by Cabinet area or topic and include federal issues of importance to the Commonwealth. Each priority includes information related to priority number, Virginia goals, request details, federal funding requested, appropriate Congressional Committee or Sub-Committee, background information, and impact of Virginia. This series may also include correspondence, presentations, procedures, and speeches.
  - Briefing (binder), 2006 Mar 27. (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Briefing (binder), 2006 Mar 27. (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 2006. (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Presentation - FY 2007 Federal Priorities, 2006 Mar 27. (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Briefing (binder), 2007 Feb 12. (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 2007. (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Event briefing, 2007. (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Procedures, 2007-2009. (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Briefing, 2008 Feb 4. (Box 26)
  - FY 2009 Federal Priorities (part I), 2008. (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - FY 2009 Federal Priorities (part II), 2008. (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - FY 2009 Federal Priorities (part III), 2008. (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Briefing, 2009 Feb 9. (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Event briefing, 2009. (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - FY 2010 Federal Priorities, 2009. (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - FY 2010 Federal Priorities, 2009. (Box 27, Folder 4)
- National Governors Association, 2006-2009., Extent: 1.4 cubic feet (4 boxes)
  The National Governors Association (NGA) files include meeting materials prepared by the NGA and event briefing binders prepared by the Virginia Liaison Office. Meeting materials include agendas, background information, correspondence, legislation, and policy position papers related to bi-annual NGA meetings. Event briefings include the daily conference schedule for the Governor and event briefing forms with meeting and conference session details, including logistics, attendance and background information. This series does not include the event briefing for the 2009 Winter meeting.
  The National Governors Association is the nonpartisan, collective voice of the nation's governors and helps governors to identify priorities and work collectively on issues of public policy and governance at the national and state level. Governors meet twice yearly to discuss common issues and challenges and promote action on national priorities. The winter meeting, held in Washington, D.C., focuses on state-federal priorities. The annual meeting, held in a different state each summer, focuses on state and intergovernmental issues. The NGA maintains four standing committees: Economic Development and Commerce; Education, Early Childhood and Workforce; Health and Human Services; and Natural Resources, to allow governors to examine and develop policy and address key national issues; and also creates special ad hoc task forces to focus on high priority issues for states.
  - Meeting materials (NGA) - Winter meeting, 2006 Feb. (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Event briefing (VLO) - Winter meeting, 2006 Feb. (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Event briefing (VLO) - Summer meeting, 2006 Aug. (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Event briefing - Winter meeting, 2007 Feb. (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Meeting materials (NGA) - Winter meeting, 2007 Feb. (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Event briefing (VLO) - Summer meeting, 2007 July. (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Event briefing (VLO) - Winter meeting, 2008 Feb. (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Event briefing (VLO) - Summer meeting, 2008 July. (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Event briefing (VLO) - Summer meeting, 2009 July. (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Meeting materials and organization information (NGA), 2008-2009. (Box 31, Folder 3)
- Southern Governors Association, 2006-2009., Extent: 1.05 cubic feet (3 boxes)
  The Southern Governors Association (SGA) files include Annual Meeting and Staff Advisory Committee (SAC) briefings prepared by the SGA, event briefing binders prepared by the Virginia Liaison Office (VLO), and subject files. Annual Meeting and SAC briefings include agendas, background information, correspondence, issue briefs, and policy position papers related to the meetings. Event briefings include the daily conference schedule for the Governor and event briefing forms with meeting and conference session details, including logistics, attendance and background information. Subject files (Council of State Governments and Climate Change Initiative) include correspondence, agreements, best practices, presentations reports, and white papers.
  The Southern Governors Association (SGA), founded in 1934, represented the common interests of Southern chief executives and provided a mechanism for promoting their concerns. SGA was a nonpartisan forum for exchanging ideas, data, information and expertise on issues of importance to southern states. SGA was officially dissolved on June 30, 2016.
  - Event briefing (VLO) - Annual meeting, 2006 July. (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Legislative briefing and Staff Advisory Committee Retreat (SGA), 2007 Jan. (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Event briefing (VLO) - Annual meeting, 2007 Aug. (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - SGA 75th Anniversary Commemoration briefing (SGA) - Planning, 2006 July. (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Staff Advisory Committe Retreat (SGA), 2008 Jan. (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Event briefing (VLO) - Annual meeting, 2008 Aug. (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Meeting briefing (SGA) - Annual meeting, 2008 Aug. (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Meeting briefing (SGA) - Annual meeting, 2009 Aug. (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - SGA and Council of State Governments, 2008-2009. (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - SGA - Climate Change Initiative, 2007-2009. (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - SGA - Climate Change Initiative, 2009. (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - SGA - Climate Change Initiative, 2009. (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - SGA - Climate Change Initiative, 2009. (Box 34, Folder 5)